<?xml version="1.0"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
   <dcterms:source>http://www.tarki.hu/cgi-bin/katalogus/tarkimain_en.pl?sorszam=TDATA-E93</dcterms:source>
   <dcterms:title>Changes in the Notions of Justice 1996. International comparative study.</dcterms:title>
   <dcterms:creator>Nagy, Ildikó</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:bibliographicCitation>TÁRKI Joint Research Center</dcterms:bibliographicCitation>
   <dcterms:date>2007-01-19</dcterms:date>
   <dcterms:subject>TÁRKI Joint Research Center  TDATA-E93: Changes in the Notions of Justice 1996. International comparative study.. data sheet. Version: 2007-01-19</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:creator>BG  <a href="http://www.tarki.hu/cgi-bin/katalogus/tarkiser_en.pl?kut=Stoyanov__Alexander">Stoyanov, Alexander</a></dcterms:creator>
	<dcterms:creator>CZ  <a href="http://www.tarki.hu/cgi-bin/katalogus/tarkiser_en.pl?kut=Mateju__Petr">Mateju, Petr</a></dcterms:creator>
	<dcterms:creator>D  <a href="http://www.tarki.hu/cgi-bin/katalogus/tarkiser_en.pl?kut=Wegener__Bernd">Wegener, Bernd</a></dcterms:creator>
	<dcterms:creator>H  <a href="http://www.tarki.hu/cgi-bin/katalogus/tarkiser_en.pl?kut=Nemenyi__Maria">Neményi, Mária</a></dcterms:creator>
	<dcterms:creator>H  <a href="http://www.tarki.hu/cgi-bin/katalogus/tarkiser_en.pl?kut=_rkeny__Antal">Örkény, Antal</a></dcterms:creator>
	<dcterms:creator>RUS  <a href="http://www.tarki.hu/cgi-bin/katalogus/tarkiser_en.pl?kut=Khakhulina__Ludmilla">Khakhulina, Ludmilla</a></dcterms:creator>
	<dcterms:creator>RUS  <a href="http://www.tarki.hu/cgi-bin/katalogus/tarkiser_en.pl?kut=Sidorenko__Svetlana">Sidorenko, Svetlana</a></dcterms:creator>
	<dcterms:creator>USA  <a href="http://www.tarki.hu/cgi-bin/katalogus/tarkiser_en.pl?kut=Kl_gel__James">Klügel, James</a></dcterms:creator>
	<dcterms:creator>USA  <a href="http://www.tarki.hu/cgi-bin/katalogus/tarkiser_en.pl?kut=Mason__David">Mason, David</a></dcterms:creator>
	<dcterms:contributor>Vitosha Research (BG)</dcterms:contributor>
	<dcterms:contributor>Center for the Study of Democracy (BG)</dcterms:contributor>
	<dcterms:contributor>STEM (CZ)</dcterms:contributor>
	<dcterms:contributor>GFM-GETAS (D)</dcterms:contributor>
	<dcterms:contributor>Hungarian Academy of Sciences Institute of Minority Research (H)</dcterms:contributor>
	<dcterms:contributor>The Russian Center for Public Opinion and Market Research (RUS)</dcterms:contributor>
   <dcterms:contributor>TÁRKI Joint Research Center</dcterms:contributor>
   <dcterms:contributor>Hungarian Academy of Sciences Institute of Minority Research</dcterms:contributor>
   <dcterms:subject>1.1</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>2004-03-00: the labels of the data file are corrected and complemented</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:description>the survey is part of the international comparative empirical survey series examined the evaluation and acceptance of the various aspects of social justice in 1991 in 12 countries, and then in 1996 in 7 countries (out of this repeated in 5 countries); the archived data file contains data from 5 countries out of the participating 7 countries: Bulgaria, Czech Republic, Hungary, Germany and Russia</dcterms:description>
	<dcterms:subject>mass political behavior, attitudes</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>equality and inequality</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>local society, region</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>social stratification and groupings</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>political institutions, public administration</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>science and technology</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>income, property and savings</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>cultural activities and participation</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>1995  1996</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:coverage>Bulgaria, Czech Republic, Hungary, Germany, Russia</dcterms:coverage>
   <dcterms:subject>person</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>survey data</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>time-series</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>The basic population in each country was the population over 18 years of age. Bulgaria: two stage sample, which was stratified by region and type of settlement at the first stage. The numberof the initial sample was 2197, and in the end 1636 persons were successully interviewed. Response rate 89,4%. Czech Republic: the number of the initial sample is 1600, number of successful interviews is 1246. Three-stage stratified random sample. At the first stage a random sample of settlements, at the second a random sample of addresses and flats were drawn. Respondents had to be chosen from among the household members older than 18 years, based on their birthday (the person who had their birthday closest to the interview date was selected). Response rate 78%. Hungary: three-stage random walking probability sample. At the first stage a random settlement sample was created, including a total of 100 settlements. At the second stage the starting points of the interviewers were randomly selected to find the appropriate house. At the third stage the selection of the appropriate household member took place using the Leslie Kish-key. The number of cases in the weighed sample is 1089. Germany: the size of the initial sample in the eastern part is 1680, in the western part also 1680 volt, out of which 1137 and 987 was successfully interviewed. It was a three-stage probability household sample, at the first stage 210 sample taking points were identified, both in the eastern and western part; at the second stage households were selected with the help of random walking, and then the respondent (stage 3). Response rate in the western part: 86,4%, eastern part: 90,7%. Russia: three-stage probability sample (one part of the details is missing). At the third stage interviewers selected the households by random walking. Respondents had to be chosen from among the household members older than 18 years, based on their birthday (the person who had their birthday closest to the interview date was selected). After the third unsuccessful visit the interviewer had to find a respondent from the household members using this same method. Out of the 2830 questionnaires 1535 were completed. Response rate: 67,1%.</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>face-to-face interview</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>B</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:rights>Publications based on TÁRKI data collections should acknowledge those sources, primary investigators and depositors.</dcterms:rights>
	<dcterms:subject>TDATA-C71</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>TDATA-C72</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>TDATA-C87</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>TDATA-E68a</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>TDATA-E68b</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>The subsamples of the individual countries can be produced by using the V1 country variable.</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>6604</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>217</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>SPSS portable datafile</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>other study-related materials:</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>English codebook</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>English documentation</dcterms:subject>
</entry>