<?xml version="1.0"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
   <dcterms:source>http://www.tarki.hu/cgi-bin/katalogus/tarkimain_en.pl?sorszam=TDATA-F14</dcterms:source>
   <dcterms:title>Causes, Way and Circumstances of Teacher Unemployment in Hungary 1998</dcterms:title>
   <dcterms:creator>Nagy, Ildikó</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:bibliographicCitation>TÁRKI Joint Research Center</dcterms:bibliographicCitation>
   <dcterms:date>2007-01-19</dcterms:date>
   <dcterms:subject>TÁRKI Joint Research Center  TDATA-F14: Causes, Way and Circumstances of Teacher Unemployment in Hungary 1998. data sheet. Version: 2007-01-19</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:creator>Liskó, Ilona</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:contributor>Hungarian Educational Research Institute</dcterms:contributor>
   <dcterms:contributor>TÁRKI Joint Research Center</dcterms:contributor>
   <dcterms:contributor>Hungarian Educational Research Institute</dcterms:contributor>
   <dcterms:subject>1.0</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:description>the reasons, methods and circumstances of teachers losing their jobs; their professional, financial, family and mental situation after losing their jobs</dcterms:description>
	<dcterms:subject>education, school</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>community, urban and rural life</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>labour and employment</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>economic conditions and indicators</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>1998</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:coverage>Hungary, except for Zala county</dcterms:coverage>
   <dcterms:subject>person</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>survey data</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>cross-section</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>Based on the database of the Ministry of Culture a settlement sample was created in which all counties were represented, excluding Zala county. At the sample selection for the sake of national representativity, the applying school maintaining local governments were ranked on the basis of the number of teachers receiving severance pay, and those 31 school maintaining local self-governments were selected which made redundant the highest number of teachers (altogether 1423 persons) with severance pay. During the data collection all of the schools were sent a postal data sheet. A total of 856 school directors receved a data sheet, and out of them 282 (33%) replied. From the schools lead by these directors the researchers selected 210 teachers who were made to retire or made redundant during the school reorganizations.</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>face-to-face interview</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>B</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:rights>Publications based on TÁRKI data collections should acknowledge those sources, primary investigators and depositors.</dcterms:rights>
   <dcterms:subject>210</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>109</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>SPSS portable datafile</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>other study-related materials:</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>Hungarian questionnaire</dcterms:subject>
</entry>